The Libretto Collection
Yale University Music Library
The Libretto Collection
1850-1940
Misc. Ms. 302
Yale University Music Library
1.5
(3 boxes)
Published opera librettos
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by composer.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of published librettos for operas, many of them associated with performances in New York or other cities.
Operas -- Librettos
- La Spia, Arditi, Luigi, 1822-1903 (Box 1)
- La Poupée / Die Puppe, Audran, Edmond, 1842-1901 (Box 1)
- The Daughter of St. Mark, Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870 (Box 1)
- Puritan's Daughter, Balfe, M. W. (Michael William), 1808-1870 (Box 1)
- Elaine, Bemberg, Herman (Box 1)
- Les Troyens, Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869 (Box 1)
- Versiegelt, Blech, Leo, 1871-1958 (Box 1)
- Princesse d'Auberge, Blockx, Jan (Box 1)
- The Immortal Hour, Boughton, Rutland (Box 1)
- Don Gil von den grünen Hosen, Braunfels, Walter (Box 1)
- Daniel, Bristow, George F. (Box 1)
- Rip Van Winkle, Bristow, George F. (Box 1)
- Shanewis, Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1881-1946 (Box 1)
- La Wally, Catalani, Alfredo (Box 1)
- Julien, Charpentier, Gustave, 1860-1956 (Box 1)
- Haschisch, Chelius, Oscar von (Box 1)
- The Pipe of Desire, Converse, Frederick (Box 1)
- Tiefland, D'Albert, Eugene (Box 1)
- Die Toten Augen, D'Albert, Eugene (Box 1)
- Cyrano, Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950 (Box 1)
- Samson, D'Aste, Ippolito (Box 1)
- The Canterbury Pilgrims, DeKoven, Reginald (Box 1)
- Messalina, De Lara, Isidore (Box 1)
- Sylvia, Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891 (Box 1)
- Linda Di Chamonix, Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848 (Box 1)
- Hellé, Duvernoy, Alphonse (Box 1)
- In the Pasha's Garden, Dwight, H.G. (Box 1)
- Der Liebe Augustin, Fall, Leo (Box 2)
- Gismonda, Février, Henri (Box 2)
- Monna Vanna, Février, Henri (Box 2)
- Stradella, Flotow, Friedrich (Box 2)
- Johannisnacht, Freudenberg, Wilhelm (Box 2)
- Die Pfahlbauer, Freudenberg, Wilhelm (Box 2)
- Leonora: A Lyrical Drama, Fry, William Henry (Box 2)
- Judith, Giacometti, Paolo (Box 2)
- Marie Antoinette, Giacometti, Paolo (Box 2)
- Fedora, Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948 (Box 2)
- Madame Sans-Gêne, Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948 (Box 2)
- Das Heimchen am Herd, Goldmark, Carl, 1830-1915 (Box 2)
- The Queen of Sheba, Goldmark, Carl, 1830-1915 (Box 2)
- Philémon et Baucis, Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893 (Box 2)
- Azora, Hadley, Henry, 1871-1937 (Box 2)
- Cleopatra's Night, Hadley, Henry, 1871-1937 (Box 2)
- Merry Mount, Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981 (Box 2)
- Madeleine, Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924 (Box 2)
- Natoma, Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924 (Box 2)
- Singvögelchen, Jacobson, Eduard (Box 2)
- Die Zirkusprinzessin, Kalman, Emmerich (Box 2)
- Der Evangelimann, Kienzl, Wilhelm (Box 2)
- Le Ranz Des Vaches, Kienzl, Wilhelm (Box 2)
- Die Tote Stadt, Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957 (Box 2)
- Jonny Spielt auf, Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991 (Box 2)
- Paganini, Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948 (Box 2)
- L'Oracolo, Leoni, Franco (Box 2)
- Saint Elizabeth, Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886 (Box 2)
- Ero e Leandro / Hero and Leander, Mancinelli, Luigi (Box 2)
- Lodoletta, Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945 (Box 2)
- The Marriage of Jeannette (bound with Delibe's Sylvia), Masse, Victor (Box 2)
- Pandora, Massena, Charles Edward Le (Box 2)
- Don Quixote, Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 (Box 2)
- Herodias, Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912 (Box 2)
- The King of Pameru, Mathews, Louis J. & Howard M. Taylor (Box 2)
- Gli Ugonotti, Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864 (Box 2)
- Il Flauto Magico, Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791 (Box 2)
- Der Trompeter von Säkkingen, Nessler, Victor G. (Box 3)
- Manru, Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941 (Box 3)
- Il Maestro di Cappella, Paër, Ferdinando, 1771-1839 (Box 3)
- A Lovers' Quarrel, Parelli, Attilio (Box 3)
- The Chimes of Corneville, Planquette, Robert (Box 3)
- Le Villi, Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924 (Box 3)
- The Carnival of Venice; or Precaution, Petrella, Errico, 1813-1877 (Box 3)
- La Fille de Roland, Rabaud, Henri (Box 3)
- Marouf, Rabaud, Henri (Box 3)
- Die wilden Schwäne, Reinecke, Carl, 1824-1910 (Box 3)
- Salammbô, Reyer, Ernesto (Box 3)
- Crispino e La Comare, Ricci, Luigi and Federico (Box 3)
- Snegurotchka, Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908 (Box 3)
- Amilie; or The Love Test, Rooke, W.M. (Box 3)
- Nero, Rubinstein, Anton (Box 3)
- Enoch Arden, Sansmann, Victor (Box 3)
- Donna Juanita, Suppe, Franz von (Box 3)
- Esmeralda, Thomas, Arthur Goring (Box 3)
- Lobetanz, Thuille, Ludwig (Box 3)
- Anima Allegra, Vittadini, Franco (Box 3)
- Schwanda der Dudelsackpfeifer, Weinberger, Jaromir (Box 3)
- Das verlorene Paradies, Wollborn, Johannes (Box 3)
- Templer and die Jüdin, Wohlbrud, Wilhelm (Box 3)
- Le Donne Curiose, Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 (Box 3)
- The Jewels of the Madonna, Wolf-Ferrari, Ermanno, 1876-1948 (Box 3)
- Francesca Da Rimini, Zandonai, Riccardo, 1883-1944 (Box 3)
- Der Dogelhändler, Zeller, Carl (Box 3)